Finding Aid for American Society for Information Science and Technology Records, 1925-2001
University of Michigan Library (Special Collections Research Center)
- CONVENTION AUDIO/VIDEO TAPES
  - 1980 Convention (Anaheim, CA)
    - 61-65, 1 folder
      - Miniforum on Bibliometrics [64] (Box 181)
      - Organizational Behavior and Information Use [65] (Box 181)
    - 66-69, 1 folder
      - Interconnection: Improving Communications for Technology Transfer Enhancement [66] (Box 181)
      - Problems in the International Transmission of Data [67] (Box 181)
      - Bibliometrics and Citation Analysis [68] (Box 181)
      - Staff Development in Communication [69] (Box 181)
    - 70-73, 1 folder
      - The Place of the Recipient in Information Science [70] (Box 181)
      - Information Services: Time Management and Setting Priorities [71] (Box 181)
      - Library Resource Sharing, Automation, and Decision Support [72] (Box 181)
      - The Role of Information Professional Societies in the Development of Government Information Policy [73 A-B] (Box 181)
    - 74-76, 1 folder
      - A New Look At the Theory-Practice Dichotomy Issues in Information and Library Science Education [74 A-B] (Box 181)
      - Examining the Public-Private Sector Interface [75] (Box 181)
      - Research on the Human-Computer Interface for Information Work [76] (Box 181)
    - 77-79, 1 folder
      - Mini-and Micro-Computer Applications [77] (Box 181)
      - User Characteristics and Studies [78] (Box 181)
      - Energy Information Design and Display [79 A-B] (Box 181)
    - 80, 1 folder
      - Medlars III System: NLM's Automation Plans for the Eighties [80] (Box 181)
    - Convention Video Cassette Tapes
      - Annual Meeting, 1 tape (Box 181)
      - Tapes 1-2 and 4-5, 4 tapes (Box 181)
      - Fifth Tape, 1 tape (Box 182)
      - Miscellaneous Videocassette, 1 tape (Box 182)
  - 1981 Convention (Washington, D.C.)
    - Business Meeting, 1 folder; 1 tape (Box 182)
    - G1-4, 1 folder
      - Plenary Session I: Information and Creativity [G1] (Box 182)
      - Plenary Session III: Alliances for Innovation and Productivity in a Changing Economy: Information Providers, Carriers, and Users [G3] (Box 182)
      - Plenary Session IV: The Sciences of Information: Looking Over the Fences [G4] (Box 182)
    - 22-25, 1 folder
      - Federal Information: Its Dissemination, Diffusion, Use and Usefulness [22] (Box 182)
      - Access to Archives: An Interdisciplinary Approach [23] (Box 182)
      - Information Materials: Management and Access [24] (Box 182)
      - Research Surveys of Library Organizations [25] (Box 182)
    - 26-29, 1 folder
      - The Creation and Distribution of Socio-Economic Databases [26] (Box 182)
      - Doctoral Forum [27] (Box 182)
      - The User Pulse: Integrating Information for Decision-Making [28] (Box 182)
      - Litigation Support Technology and Use [29] (Box 182)
    - 31-34, 1 folder
      - Computer Graphics [31] (Box 182)
      - World Information Issues; Part I: Overview [32] (Box 182)
      - Training for Online Searching [33] (Box 182)
      - User's Needs Come First in Online and Other Systems [34] (Box 182)
    - 35-38, 1 folder
      - New Directions for Information Science Education [35] (Box 182)
      - Assessing Energy Information Needs for the Future [36] (Box 182)
      - Designing Numeric Database Systems [38] (Box 182)
    - 40-43, 1 folder
      - World Information Issues; Part 2: Information Transfer to Less-Developed Countries (LDCs) [40] (Box 183)
      - Current Research in the Information Sciences; Part 1 [42] (Box 183)
      - Transfer of Information to the User Community [43] (Box 183)
    - 45-47, 1 folder
      - Computer Literacy: What Is It? How Do We Teach It? [45] (Box 183)
      - Use of Numeric Databases in the Corporate, Academic and Business Environments [46 A-B] (Box 183)
      - Managing Office Productivity [47 A-B] (Box 183)
    - 51-53, 1 folder
      - World Information Issues; Part 3: Case Studies for Specific Less-Developed Countries (LDCs) [51] (Box 183)
      - Federal Statistical Data Access Programs [52] (Box 183)
      - Stalking the (Wild) Referee: Journal Editors Look at the Refereeing Process [53] (Box 183)
    - 54-56, 1 folder
      - Online Databases: Resources By and About Women, Minorities, and the Disabled: Analysis and Case Studies [54] (Box 183)
      - Enhancement of Information Transfer [55] (Box 183)
      - Cost-Effective Instant Information [56] (Box 183)
    - 61-66, 1 folder
      - On the Construction and Use of Creative Ontologies: A Concerted Defense Against Solipsism in Information and Its Management [61] (Box 183)
      - Research Advances in Information Science [65 A-B] (Box 183)
      - Legislative Issues [66] (Box 183)
    - 67-68, 1 folder
      - Computers and Music [67 A-B] (Box 183)
      - Update on Information and Referral [68 A] (Box 183)
    - 68-69, 1 folder
      - Update on Information and Referral [68 B] (Box 183)
      - New and/or Innovative Approaches to Information Publishing [69 A-B] (Box 183)
    - 70-73, 1 folder
      - How to Plan and Select an Online Catalog [70 A-B] (Box 183)
      - Medical Information Networks [71] (Box 183)
      - Computer Conferencing [73] (Box 183)
    - 77-78, 1 folder
      - Barriers to Information for Industry [77 A-B] (Box 183)
      - Associative Indexing and Searching: History, Applications and State of the Art [78 A-B] (Box 183)
    - 79, 1 folder
      - Office Automation Report [79 A-B] (Box 183)
    - 80-82, 1 folder
      - Through the Looking Glass: Publishing 1990 [80 A-B] (Box 183)
      - The User Interface: A Major Barrier to the Diffusion of the Microcomputer [82] (Box 183)
    - 83-87, 1 folder
      - Career Paths for Information Professionals [83] (Box 183)
      - Network Advisory Committee Open Forum [84] (Box 183)
      - A Library and Information Science National Research Agenda for the 1980s A Progress Report [86 A-B] (Box 183)
      - Multi-System Searching [87] (Box 183)
    - 88-89, 1 folder
      - Automated Acquisitions: Integration W/Other Automated Systems [88 A-B] (Box 183)
      - Management Information for Information Managers: The Economic Impact of Information [89 A-B] (Box 183)
    - 90-99, 1 folder
      - Use of Small Computers in Medicine [90] (Box 183)
      - The Meaning of User Studies [99] (Box 183)
    - 100-103, 1 folder
      - Use of Managerial Principles in Information Work [100] (Box 184)
      - The Bridge Between Information Science and the Automated Office [101] (Box 184)
      - Beyond the Classroom: Varieties in Continuing Education [102] (Box 184)
      - Information Organization in the Arts and Humanities [103] (Box 184)
    - 104-107, 1 folder
      - Federal Research Funding for Information Science [104] (Box 184)
      - International Transferability of Information [105 A-B] (Box 184)
      - Micrographics and Word Processing [107] (Box 184)
    - 110-118, 1 folder
      - Office Automation [110] (Box 184)
      - Natural Language Text Processing [117] (Box 184)
      - Progress in Document Retrieval and Document Selection [118] (Box 184)
    - 120-124, 1 folder
      - Current Research in the Information Sciences; Part 2 [120] (Box 184)
      - Classification Research Forum [121] (Box 184)
      - Basic Approaches to Fundamental Research in Information Science [124] (Box 184)
    - 127-129, 1 folder
      - Videotex [127] (Box 184)
      - Studies of Computer-Mediated Communication Systems: A Syntheses of Findings [128] (Box 184)
      - Software for Information Management Systems [129] (Box 184)
    - 130-133, 1 folder
      - Applications of Mini-and Micro-Computers for Information Systems; Part 1 [130] (Box 184)
      - Indexing for Information Resource Management [131] (Box 184)
      - Models of Interpretation in Observation and Communication [132] (Box 184)
      - Policies for the Dissemination of Federal Information [133] (Box 184)
    - 135-138, 1 folder
      - Machine Translation in the 1980s [135 A-B] (Box 184)
      - Data Quality Control: Theory and Application [136] (Box 184)
      - Applications of Mini-and Micro-Computers for Information Systems; Part 2 [137] (Box 184)
      - Humanizing the User/Computer Interface [138] (Box 184)
    - 141, 1 folder
      - [Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (PL 96 511)] [141] (Box 184)
        (title taken from tape)
  - 1982 Convention (Columbus, Ohio)
    - G1-3, 1 folder
      - Plenary Session I: Keynote Address: Office Innovation [G1] (Box 184)
      - Plenary Session II: Panel on How the Executive Views His Own Information Problems: What the Situation Was Five Years Ago, What It Is Now, and What It Will Be In the Next Five Years [G2] (Box 184)
      - Plenary Session III [G3] (Box 184)
    - 21-25, 1 folder
      - Briefing 1: Computer Communication Networks: An Overview [21] (Box 184)
      - Contributed Paper Session 1: Development and Use of Specialized Databases [22] (Box 184)
      - Contributed Paper Session 2: Research in Text Processing [23] (Box 184)
      - Product/Service Review 1 [25] (Box 184)
    - 26-29, 1 folder
      - Symposium on United States Information Science Education for Foreign Students [26] (Box 184)
      - Symposium on Information Explosion or Information Indigestion [27] (Box 184)
      - Panel on Coordination and Management of Automated Services [28] (Box 184)
      - Symposium on International Uses of Non-Print Materials [29] (Box 184)
    - 34-39, 1 folder
      - Contributed Paper Session 3: New Modes of Information Interaction in the Organization: 1 [34] (Box 184)
      - Panel on Future Trends in the Delivery of Information [36] (Box 184)
      - Symposium on Man-Machine Interaction [37] (Box 184)
      - Special Symposium 1: The Results and Implications of the ERIC Cost and Usage Study [39] (Box 184)
    - 40-42, 1 folder
      - Exhibitors' New Products Seminar [40 A-B] (Box 184)
      - Special Panel Session 1: Information Entrepreneurship: Starting Out: Part 1 [42 A-B] (Box 184)
    - 46-48, 1 folder
      - Contributed Paper Session 4: Networks and Information Exchange [46] (Box 184)
      - Symposium on Ideas for Fundamental Research on Man-Machine Interaction: An Open Forum [47] (Box 184)
      - Panel on Information Systems Consultants Overseas: Change Agents in Need of Change? [48] (Box 184)
    - 50-54, 1 folder
      - Special Panel Session 2: Ohio in Information History [50] (Box 184)
      - Symposium on Classification of Noise [54] (Box 184)
    - 60-62, 1 folder
      - Contributed Paper Session 5: Information Systems and Human Behavior [60] (Box 184)
      - Contributed Paper Session 6: New Modes of Information Interaction in the Organization: 2 [61] (Box 184)
      - Information Science Theater Presentation 2: Computer Imagery As a Communications Tool [62] (Box 184)
    - 63-67, 1 folder
      - Symposium on Computer Processing of Chinese Library Materials and Computer-Assisted Chinese Language Instruction; Part 1 [63] (Box 184)
      - Symposium on Selective Technologies for the Dissemination of Information [65] (Box 184)
      - Special Panel Session 3: Home Information Systems [66] (Box 184)
      - Special Presentation 1: The Human Side of Future Information Systems [67] (Box 184)
    - 72-75, 1 folder
      - Symposium on Online Retrieval of Fine Arts Information [72] (Box 185)
      - Symposium on Subject Access to Numeric Databases [73] (Box 185)
      - Symposium on Existing Energy and Environmental Information Systems [74] (Box 185)
      - Symposium on Selection Criteria in Electronic Data Publishing [75] (Box 185)
    - 76-77, 1 folder
      - Panel on the Online Public Access Catalog Projects: Findings [76 A-B] (Box 185)
      - Special Panel Session 4: Information Entrepreneurship: Within an Organization: Part 2 [77 A-B] (Box 185)
    - 78-79, 1 folder
      - Special Presentation 2: How to Use the Beilstein Handbook of Organic Chemistry [78 A-B] (Box 185)
      - Symposium on Computer Processing of Chinese Library Materials and Computer-Assisted Chinese Language Instruction; Part 2 [79 A-B] (Box 185)
    - 80-84, 1 folder
      - Contributed Paper Session 7: Organizational Interactions in Publishing [80] (Box 185)
      - Product/Service Review Panel 2: Automated Serial Control Systems [81] (Box 185)
      - Symposium on Information for Waste Management [82] (Box 185)
      - Panel on Outreach, Training, and Evaluation: A Cycle for Microcomputer Use [83] (Box 185)
      - Symposium on Numeric Database Services: Where Do We Stand? Where Do We Go? [84] (Box 185)
    - 95-99, 1 folder
      - Contributed Paper Session 8: Advances in Understanding of Information Science [95] (Box 185)
      - Contributed Paper Session 9: Evaluation of Information Systems [96] (Box 185)
      - Product/Service Review 2 [97] (Box 185)
      - Product/Service Review Panel 3: Electronic Mail [98] (Box 185)
      - Symposium on Integration of Information Resources in the Office of the Future [99] (Box 185)
    - 101-106, 1 folder
      - Special Symposium 3: Information Management for the Legal Profession [101] (Box 185)
      - Special Symposium 4: Research in Subject Access at OCLC [102 A-B] (Box 185)
      - Contributed Paper Session 10: Teaching of Library and Information Sciences [104] (Box 185)
      - Information Science Theater Presentation 3: Battle of the Library Superstars: Professional Techniques in Library Instruction Video Tape Production [106] (Box 185)
    - 111-115, 1 folder
      - Special Symposium 5: Directions, Problems, and Opportunities in Automated Litigation Support [110] (Box 185)
      - Briefing 4: Information Theory as Applied to Information Science [111] (Box 185)
      - Contributed Paper Session 12: Monitoring and Evaluation of Information Interactions [112] (Box 185)
      - Panel on Online Searching Process, Productivity, and Payoff [115] (Box 185)
    - 116-119, 1 folder
      - Panel on How Technical Innovation Reaches the Classroom and Theoretical Research Reaches the Field [116] (Box 185)
      - Symposium on Trends in Information Technology in the Legal Environment [117] (Box 185)
      - Special Panel Session 6: The Role of the Institution in the Information Community [118] (Box 185)
      - Tutorial on So You Want to be an Author [119 A-B] (Box 185)
    - 120-126, 1 folder
      - Contributed Paper Session 13: Aspects of the Delivery of Information Services [120] (Box 185)
      - Contributed Paper Session 14: Applications of New Technologies to Information Systems [121] (Box 185)
    - 120-126, 1 folder
      - Contributed Paper Session 15: Information Interactions Among Health Science Professionals [122] (Box 185)
      - Symposium on Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance: A Holistic View of Quality as It Relates to Information Science [125] (Box 185)
      - Special Symposium 6: Tools for Information Resources Management [126] (Box 185)
    - 136-139, 1 folder
      - Panel on the Role of the For-Profit Sector in Library Networks [136] (Box 185)
      - Contributed Paper Session 16: Educational Applications of Information Technology [137] (Box 185)
      - Contributed Paper Session 17: Research in Library Automation; Part 1 [138] (Box 185)
      - Panel on End-User Databases [139] (Box 185)
    - 140-143, 1 folder
      - Doctoral Forum [140] (Box 185)
      - Symposium on the Perspectives on the Study of Human-Computer Interaction [142] (Box 185)
      - Special Symposium 7: The Value of Information [143 A-B] (Box 185)
    - 146-148, 1 folder
      - Contributed Paper Session 18: Research in Library Automation; Part 2 [146] (Box 185)
      - Contributed Paper Session 19: Providing Access to Information in the Medical and Health Sciences [147] (Box 185)
      - Information Science Theater Presentation 4: The Magic of Animation: The Disney Studio's Approach to Communication Through Art [148] (Box 185)
    - 150-155, 1 folder
      - Panel on Unix in the Library [150] (Box 185)
      - Contributed Paper Session 20: Human Factors in Information System Design [152] (Box 185)
      - Contributed Paper Session 21: Information Interactions in the University Library [153] (Box 185)
      - Late-Breaking Developments [155] (Box 185)
    - 156-158, 1 folder
      - Panel on Information Management Education [156] (Box 185)
      - Symposium on Recent Topics in Medical Information Systems [157] (Box 185)
      - Special Panel Session 8: The Application of Research to Information Retrieval Systems [158] (Box 185)
    - Unidentified tapes, 2 folders; 9 tapes (Box 185)
  - Information Science: What Is It?: slide presentation, 1979, 6 slide trays and 3 audio cassettes; 6 minutes 15 seconds
    - Left projector tray, copies 1-3, and audio (Box 186)
    - Right projector tray, copies 1-3, and audio (Box 187)
- Restricted Materials
  - Materials from various series (Box 188)